<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tanisha Hampden</title>
    <description>This is a blog and portfolio by me. 
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 14:46:24 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 14:46:24 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building A Wikipedia Viewer</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-i-learned-from-building-a-wikipedia-viewer&quot;&gt;What I learned from building a Wikipedia Viewer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not at all a tutorial but a reflection of the things that I learned and the problems I faced while building a Wikipedia viewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;event-handlers&quot;&gt;Event Handlers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow I got into the habit of adding &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;onclick&lt;/code&gt; events to html files. This works fine but my mentor mentioned that it’s better practice to keep all of your Javascript self-contained to make debugging easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While rewriting the functions that required an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;addEventListener&lt;/code&gt; object I ran into the error below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;error: Cannot read property &#39;addEventListener&#39; of null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that the function returned &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; because it executed before the DOM was fully loaded. I fixed this problem by adding &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en/docs/Web/API/GlobalEventHandlers/onload&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;window.onload&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. MDN notes that “The &lt;strong&gt;load event&lt;/strong&gt; fires at the end of the document loading process. At this point, all of the objects in the document are in the DOM, and all the images, scripts, links and sub-frames have finished loading.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;scope&quot;&gt;Scope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was reminded a few times of the importance of understanding scope and how it can affect your code structure. I had to move functions around a bit to ensure that all of my variables were able to be accessed properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, I would get an error that a variable is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt;. To fix this I’d either make the variable global or I would move the function to allow it access to that variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cors&quot;&gt;CORS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my biggest hurdle throughout this project. I spent several days reading about cross-origin resource sharing and trying several known hacks to enable CORS from the client side. I tried to manually &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Access_control_CORS&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;setRequestHeaders&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; within my xhr request, I tried to make my request using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://plainjs.com/javascript/ajax/jsonp-ajax-requests-50/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;JSONP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; method, and I even attempted to add CORS support from the server side. In the end, solving the problem was specific to the Wikipedia API and if I would have read the docs a bit more carefully I could have saved myself several days of headache. I am happy that I got such an in-depth lesson on how CORS works. I will also &lt;em&gt;ALWAYS&lt;/em&gt; read the docs thoroughly from now on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude, I probably spent more time than necessary banging my head up against the wall instead of just asking for help but I don’t think I will run into any of these problems in this manner again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the source code and live preview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanham/wiki-viewer&quot;&gt;Wikipedia Viewer code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;265&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;0&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;yVpaQg&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;js,result&quot; data-user=&quot;tanham2122&quot; data-embed-version=&quot;2&quot; data-pen-title=&quot;Wikipedia Viewer&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/tanham2122/pen/yVpaQg/&quot;&gt;Wikipedia Viewer&lt;/a&gt; by Tanisha Hampden (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/tanham2122&quot;&gt;@tanham2122&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/12/07/building-a-wikipedia-viewer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/12/07/building-a-wikipedia-viewer.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My RC Start Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-rc-start&quot;&gt;What is RC Start?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recurse Center describes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recurse.com/blog/99-free-one-on-one-mentorship-for-new-programmers&quot;&gt;RC Start&lt;/a&gt; as an experiment that “offers one-on-one advice from members of the Recurse Center community”. If you are selected for RC Start, you’ll get three 45-minute one-on-one sessions with an RC alum(in-person or video chat) and access to the RC Start community through a private forum (check out the link for more specifics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-i-apply&quot;&gt;Why did I apply?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I came across Recurse Center and RC Start, I had just started to become serious about teaching myself to code. I fell in love with RC’s mission and description of community and I immediately wanted to be apart of it. I had no previous coding background but I was eager to learn and I knew that having a mentor could help answer some of the questions that I’d been stuck on and help point me in the right direction. RC Start seemed like the perfect program from me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-were-the-one-on-one-sessions-like&quot;&gt;What were the one-on-one sessions like?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I understand it, every RC Start experience is different based on schedules and other factors so my experience may not look like anyone else’s. Because I’ve been nomadic, I was paired with a remote mentor. When I began the program I was in Italy and my mentor was based in Singapore. Throughout the program, I went from Italy to France to Ireland so we always had a 6 or 7 hour time difference. This was not a  problem because I was flexible and she gave me plenty of options to meet. Our sessions were a bit spaced out for scheduling reasons but also to give me time in-between to implement what we talked about and learn on my own. In between each session, my mentor sent me resources and I sent her updates on my progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had 4 sessions total (1 intro and 3 official). Leading up to each session, I made notes about what I wanted to ask and/or work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;introductory-session---june-11th-2016&quot;&gt;Introductory Session - June 11th, 2016&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this first session we learned a bit about one another, talked about what I have been working on and what I wanted out of our sessions. It was a great start to our journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;session-1---june-26th-2016&quot;&gt;Session 1 - June 26th, 2016&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our first official session she did a code review of my portfolio code, talked about DOM manipulation, and briefly talked about making art with code. She suggested that I look into image processing and other generative art because of my photography background. She also suggested Jekyll for my portfolio and urged me to get it online using gh-pages for practice with git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, I learned how to use ‘ping’ using the terminal because our connection was lost a few times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;session-2---july-19-2016&quot;&gt;Session 2 - July 19, 2016&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading up to this session I wrote up my learning priorities and a list of specific questions about what I had been working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of this session we used screen sharing to walk through building a JavaScript carousel and she showed me examples of DOM Manipulation using JavaScript. This was the most helpful session up until this point. Hearing her talk through why she did certain things and about how she thought about the code solidified some of my understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this session I began building my own small JavaScript projects and finding real-world applications for the scripts that I was learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we talked about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my newly published Jekyll site and issues I had faced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;open source&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Git and Github (writing proper commit messages, git commands, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;setting up a local server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;session-3---september-6th-2016&quot;&gt;Session 3 - September 6th, 2016&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our final session, we pair programmed on my local weather app. With my mentor’s help, I changed 2 jQuery scripts to plain JavaScript. In the process she also showed me several debugging techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, pairing showed me that I need to work on communicating more clearly (out loud and in real-time) what I am coding and what I don’t understand. This skill is necessary when working in groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was such a valuable experience and I can’t wait to pair more with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience was overwhelmingly positive. I really loved my mentor and learned a ton from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, I would have down a few things differently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;been more active within the RC Start community (in the community forum)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;asked more questions in between sessions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;paired on all 3 sessions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;asked for more code reviews and specific feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in RC Start or RC Retreat, check them out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recurse.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/09/08/my-rc-start-experience.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/09/08/my-rc-start-experience.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Before This Year is Over</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I began learning to code seriously about 4 months ago. I have come amazingly far from not knowing exactly what computer programming was a year ago to today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what I would like to work on before 2016 is over&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;become-a-javascript-ninja&quot;&gt;Become a JavaScript Ninja&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I know enough JavaScript to be dangerous. I can write small programs and solve simple algorithms but anything bigger and I am off in Google land trying to figure out what I have gotten myself into. Here are some of the JS projects that I have worked on so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tanham.github.io/js-rocket/rocket.html&quot;&gt;JS Rocket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/tanham2122/pen/WxzBgE&quot;&gt;Random Quote Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/tanham2122/pen/kXJQzK&quot;&gt;Local Weather app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JS Calculator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To Do List App&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize that a few months is not enough time to become a JS expert but I plan to deeply study the fundamentals of JavaScript and how it works while writing an absurd amount of code. By the end of the year, I would like to have confidence that I can solve most things with JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan of attack is simple: write code, read code, read books, and talk JS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write code - write at least one JS app each week, write JS daily&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read code -  Periodically read JavaScript code (maybe in a pair or group?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reading list - Think Like a Programmer, Eloquent JavaScript, You Don’t Know JS, JavaScript: The Good Parts, (I am taking suggestions)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk JS - Ask questions, pontificate, teach what I know, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;build-a-body-of-art-work-using-code&quot;&gt;Build a Body of Art Work Using Code&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love art. I also love the idea using code to make art. CSS animation, image processing and other generative art fascinates me. I would like to spend time digging deeper into this kind of programming and making some of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create 3-5 pieces of art with code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design and program a computer game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;build-an-app&quot;&gt;Build an App&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to build an app that keeps tracks of several kinds personal data in one place(i.e health metrics, finances, daily log, stress levels, food intake, etc.). On any given day, I would like to be able to analyze any week’s or month’s personal data to find areas of self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an extension of a self-experiment that I have been working on for some time. When I put all the important metrics in one place, I always find ways I can improve my quality of life so I would like to use software to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;also&quot;&gt;Also:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;find a community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;contribute to Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;feel confident when introducing myself as a web developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/08/29/before-this-year-is-over.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/08/29/before-this-year-is-over.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Crave Community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I crave community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past eight months, I have been traveling all around Europe, searching for my community. I have been to England, Spain, Italy, France, and Ireland and in each place I have found what I like to call the 5-percenters. People who beleive in pursuing dreams and travel and living life as loudly as possible. People who chose not to judge based on silly things like skin color and sexual orientation. People who actually want to know who you are. It’s been transformative. I’ve learned so much about this part of the world. I have so much more to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important lesson so far is that the most effective way to learn something is to surround myself with others who are just as passionate (about that something) as I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I am looking for my code community. I am looking for people who love to code. I’d love to find those who may look a bit different than the traditional web developer. I’d love to spend hours a day with my new code community, working out problems and coming up with new ways of doing things. I’d love to dive right into the deep end and code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search begins…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/08/15/i-crave-community.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/08/15/i-crave-community.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacking my learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had to hack my learning. Over the past few weeks, I found that I wasn’t picking up JavaScript as well as I’d like with fCC. I got bored with tutorials and I figured out a pattern to solving problems by imitation rather then thinking through it. I am naturally a corner cutter and so without the fundamental understanding I flew through the material with patterns I picked up solving the easy stuff. For me to understand something I have to dig into what’s under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to fCC, I tried Codecademy, reading JavaScript books, looking at MDN and other online resources. Some stuff was boring and other stuff was incredibly dense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had an ‘aha’ moment when my RC start mentor walked me through building a JavaScript image slider using Codepen and screen-casting. As she built the slider, I listened to her talk her way through why she did things. I am comfortable with JavaScript syntax but I usually get caught up in thinking computationally. It helped so much to hear her talk through her process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I am beginning to understand what’s most important to my learning. I need a fundamental understanding of concepts and I need interactive examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the right amount of community and self awareness pertaining to one’s learning style can save a ton of time and trouble learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/code/2016/07/25/hacking-my-learning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/code/2016/07/25/hacking-my-learning.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog Test!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 20:40:43 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/22/blog-test.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/22/blog-test.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Code Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a public record my goals and learning strategy to hold myself accountable and to share more of my journey. To help measure my progress I will keep this page active by adding links to my code and sharing adjustments that I make. Here are the 5 things that I am focusing on over the next three months:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-stuff&quot;&gt;Building stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This portfolio site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CS50 psets
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;pset 0 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://scratch.mit.edu/projects/117240207/&quot;&gt;MIT Scratch project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;pset 1 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/tanham/0f614de419354df1afd946c57d480fe4&quot;&gt;Water&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/tanham/5cc739d58d8f3619177d8192fcbf3d19&quot;&gt;Mario&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;pset 2&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;pset 3&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;pset 4&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;pset 5&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;pset 6&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;pset 7&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;pset 8&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fCC projects
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/tanham2122/pen/WxzBgE&quot;&gt;Random Quote Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Local Weather App&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wikipedia Viewer&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Twitch.tv JSON api&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSS animation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vanilla Javascript features&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jekyll themes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/collection/XRRQzY/&quot;&gt;Codepen reference pens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tanham21.github.io/js-rocket/rocket.html&quot;&gt;JS Rocket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deep-learning-front-end-resources&quot;&gt;Deep Learning (Front-end Resources)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/&quot;&gt;edX CS50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.com/tanham21&quot;&gt;freeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Developer Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ecmascript.org/docs.php&quot;&gt;EMCAscript standard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gitbook.com/book/frontendmasters/front-end-handbook/details&quot;&gt;Front End Handbook pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;writing&quot;&gt;Writing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a goal to post at least weekly to this blog. I’d like to write about things that I have learned, problems that I encounter and other tech related (and non-related) things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part I am learning alone, just me and my computer. Because I am currently traveling, language barriers and location make it so I am rarely able to attend meetups or meet other Devs in real life. To hack this I am apart of a few online groups that focus on creating community for people like me. I am also apart of Recurse center’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recurse.com/blog/99-free-one-on-one-mentorship-for-new-programmers&quot;&gt;RC start program&lt;/a&gt; so I have access to a mentor and that community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still learning how to use these communities as resources and help wherever I can but I’d like to make this a big part of my learning and overall coding journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;open-source&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very interested in Open Source. I’ve already benefited tremendously from OSS and I would like to contribute. I believe in making technology accessible and I think it is a great way to give back to a community that has already taught me so much. Over the next three months I will pick an open source project to contribute to regularly. I will updated this post with my progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/18/code-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/18/code-goals.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building This Jekyll Site</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing and building a new website for myself was the reason that I wanted to learn to code. I was so fed up with the free resources available to me (an at the time non-techie) and I wanted to learn to make my own website. I had no idea that I’d get so into it, but here I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wire-framing&quot;&gt;Wire framing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m new to designing websites but I know what I like. I watched a few Youtube videos about wire framing, with hopes of understanding some of the thought processes behind the practice and what things to take note of in the beginning. I kept my eyes open as I perused the web for designs that I liked and then I sketched a several designs over a few days. I nixed most of my initial ideas (some that I still like) because I didn’t think I could get it to work in the browser or because they were just bad. At this point, many of my ideas are a remix of some of the things that I admire online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototyping-in-codepen&quot;&gt;Prototyping in Codepen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I coded 3 iterations of my design in Codepen to prototype. I like Codepen for it’s auto preview feature. I thought it might be nice to immediately see how my code came to life - and it was. I chose to use Bootstrap to create my layout fast. Here is one iteration of the design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;265&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;0&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;vKJOzQ&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;html,result&quot; data-user=&quot;tanham2122&quot; data-embed-version=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/tanham2122/pen/vKJOzQ/&quot;&gt;vKJOzQ&lt;/a&gt; by Tanisha Hampden (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/tanham2122&quot;&gt;@tanham2122&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had plenty help every step of the way. For wire framing I watched a video from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PQO47_AP6lo&quot;&gt;DevTip&lt;/a&gt; and bits and pieces from others to try to put myself on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lilchen.com/blog/site-redesign-process/&quot;&gt;Lil Chen’s site redesign article&lt;/a&gt; was such a big help in having a peek into how someone more experienced may go about the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also read about writing clean and modular code with &lt;a href=&quot;http://csswizardry.com/2013/01/mindbemding-getting-your-head-round-bem-syntax/&quot;&gt;BEM&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://toddmotto.com/getting-started-with-object-orientated-css-oocss-creating-a-button-kit/&quot;&gt;OOCSS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://learnlayout.com/&quot;&gt;Learn layout&lt;/a&gt; was a good help for some CSS refreshers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.crisp.se/2016/01/25/henrikkniberg/making-sense-of-mvp&quot;&gt;Minimum viable product&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t say that I have hard fast followed any of these things. I have to remind myself of the things that I learn and want to adopt at every turn but they serve as good jumping off points. I will say that at some point I had to stop trying to take advice and just code. The resources were great to get me started but I had to dig in before analysis paralysis set in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enter-jekyll&quot;&gt;Enter Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I downloaded and ran Jekyll for the first time with the help of their amazing &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to use the default Jekyll theme as a starting point. I ran into several problems that I am still working out and in retrospect I should have began with a clean slate but working the kinks was a tremendous learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One problem that I had was using vanilla CSS instead of Sass. The default Jekyll theme comes with Sass styling. I pasted my CSS into a new file and added to the project - the Sass styling and my CSS was competing with each other. I liked some of the Sass styling but I ended up deleting the entire Sass files so I can have full control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still learning Jekyll and I’m constantly amazed by how powerful it is. My design and overall website will continue to evolve as I learn and experiment more.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/13/building-this-jekyll-site.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/13/building-this-jekyll-site.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
